<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://al6ert.github.io/website.stage/en/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://al6ert.github.io/website.stage/en/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2026-02-19T16:14:48+00:00</updated><id>https://al6ert.github.io/website.stage/en/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Persualia</title><subtitle>Agencia de marketing conversacional. Copy que conecta y resultados que se pueden medir.</subtitle><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">3 mistakes that ruin your Christmas ecommerce campaigns (and how to avoid them)</title><link href="https://al6ert.github.io/website.stage/en/news/marketing/ecommerce/2025/12/01/3-mistakes-christmas-ecommerce-campaigns/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="3 mistakes that ruin your Christmas ecommerce campaigns (and how to avoid them)" /><published>2025-12-01T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-12-01T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://al6ert.github.io/website.stage/en/news/marketing/ecommerce/2025/12/01/3-mistakes-christmas-ecommerce-campaigns</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://al6ert.github.io/website.stage/en/news/marketing/ecommerce/2025/12/01/3-mistakes-christmas-ecommerce-campaigns/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="practical-guide-to-lift-results-conversion-and-roas-during-the-most-competitive-season-of-the-year">Practical guide to lift results, conversion and ROAS during the most competitive season of the year.</h2>

<p>Every December brands push their <strong>Christmas campaigns</strong> hoping to skyrocket online sales… yet many end up losing profitability without a clear reason. The strongest month for ecommerce is also the most complex: CPMs increase, competition intensifies and <strong>any tactical mistake can have a huge impact on your cost per result.</strong></p>

<p>At Persualia we manage high-performance ecommerce campaigns and we see the same pattern year after year: identical mistakes that slow down conversions and waste opportunities.<br />
Here we break down <strong>the 3 most frequent Christmas campaign errors</strong> and how to avoid them so your digital strategy performs better in 2025.</p>

<h3 id="1-swapping-creatives-too-early-or-too-late">1. Swapping creatives too early (or too late)</h3>

<p>How you manage <strong>Christmas campaign creatives</strong> dictates whether you can scale sales or stall out.</p>

<p>In December, ad platforms (Meta Ads, Google Ads…) need more time to leave the learning phase because competition is higher. Still, many brands replace creatives impulsively as soon as they see short-term swings in performance.</p>

<h4 id="why-is-this-a-problem">Why is this a problem?</h4>

<ul>
  <li>It restarts learning right when the campaign was stabilising.</li>
  <li>Costs go up right in the middle of peak season.</li>
  <li>You lose the accumulated signals the algorithm needs to optimise.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="how-to-avoid-it-in-2025">How to avoid it in 2025</h4>

<ul>
  <li>Plan <strong>two holiday creative waves</strong> from the start.</li>
  <li>Evaluate performance with enough statistically relevant data.</li>
  <li>Avoid radical changes during demand peaks.</li>
  <li>Keep consistency between creatives, messaging and the landing page.</li>
</ul>

<p>Managed properly, your creatives can dramatically lift <strong>Christmas ROAS</strong>.</p>

<h3 id="2-skipping-a-landing-page-tailored-for-christmas">2. Skipping a landing page tailored for Christmas</h3>

<p>One of the keys to improving conversion in December is building <strong>landing pages created specifically for holiday campaigns</strong>.<br />
Yet many brands still send traffic to generic product pages.</p>

<h4 id="why-is-this-a-critical-mistake-for-christmas-ecommerce">Why is this a critical mistake for Christmas ecommerce?</h4>

<p>Because in December people are looking for <strong>gifts</strong>, not just products. They need speed and a clear promise.</p>

<p>Generic landings lead to:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Lower conversion rate.</li>
  <li>Misalignments between ad promise and destination.</li>
  <li>Lower Quality Scores in Google Ads.</li>
  <li>Higher cost per acquisition.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="how-to-optimise-your-holiday-landing">How to optimise your holiday landing</h4>

<ul>
  <li>Create themed landings with bundles, offers or “gifts that matter”.</li>
  <li>Simplify: less scroll, fewer options, more focus.</li>
  <li>Highlight December proof points: fast shipping, guarantees, easy returns.</li>
  <li>Mirror the look &amp; feel of your campaign creatives.</li>
</ul>

<p>A well-crafted landing can boost sales even without adding budget.</p>

<h3 id="3-pausing-campaigns-when-costs-go-up-the-mistake-that-burns-the-most-money">3. Pausing campaigns when costs go up (the mistake that burns the most money)</h3>

<p>In December <strong>CPMs always rise</strong>. It is normal and it hits the entire ecommerce sector.<br />
The most expensive mistake is pausing campaigns just because cost per result increases.</p>

<h4 id="what-happens-when-you-pause-your-holiday-campaigns">What happens when you pause your holiday campaigns?</h4>

<ul>
  <li>You lose the competitive momentum you had built.</li>
  <li>The algorithm “forgets” part of its learning.</li>
  <li>When you reactivate, you come back more expensive and with worse performance.</li>
  <li>It takes days to regain stability (and in December, days are gold).</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="how-to-handle-it-properly">How to handle it properly</h4>

<ul>
  <li>Treat December as a strategic month, not a cheap one.</li>
  <li>Adjust budgets smoothly, without hard stops.</li>
  <li>Keep campaigns live through the key peaks.</li>
  <li>Analyse trends, not micro day-to-day swings.</li>
</ul>

<p>The secret behind strong <strong>Christmas performance campaigns</strong> is not spending more, but <strong>not breaking what already works</strong>.</p>

<h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>

<p>The best Christmas ecommerce campaigns are not the ones with the biggest budgets, but the ones that <strong>plan ahead, stay stable and optimise each phase thoughtfully</strong>.</p>

<p>If you want your holiday campaign to truly deliver, remember:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Anticipation beats improvisation.</li>
  <li>Christmas campaigns are not improvised: they are prepared weeks in advance, not once December has already started.</li>
  <li>If you want a better campaign next year, the work starts in January by reviewing data and learnings.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<p>Would you like us to review your Christmas campaign and spot improvement opportunities?</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>At Persualia we analyse funnels, creatives and campaign structures so your investment performs better.</p>
</blockquote>

<div class="text-center not-prose"><a class="btn btn-primary text-primary-content btn-lg" href="mailto:mail@persualia.com">Book a free review here</a></div>

<hr />

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#Ecommerce</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#ChristmasCampaigns</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#DigitalMarketing</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#ROAS</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#Performance</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#LandingPages</code></p>]]></content><author><name>Coral Costa</name></author><category term="news" /><category term="marketing" /><category term="ecommerce" /><category term="ChristmasCampaigns" /><category term="Ecommerce" /><category term="ROAS" /><category term="Creatives" /><category term="LandingPages" /><category term="MetaAds" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Practical guide to avoid the most expensive mistakes in creatives, landings and budget management during the most competitive ecommerce month.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://al6ert.github.io/website.stage/en/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/assets/images/posts/2025-12-01-3-errores-campanas-navidad-ecommerce%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Holiday%20illustration%20with%20ecommerce%20dashboards%20and%20gifts%20representing%20campaign%20decisions%22,%20%22caption%22=%3E%22Planning%20creatives,%20landings%20and%20budget%20keeps%20December%20from%20wrecking%20profitability.%22,%20%22width%22=%3E2816,%20%22height%22=%3E1536%7D" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://al6ert.github.io/website.stage/en/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/assets/images/posts/2025-12-01-3-errores-campanas-navidad-ecommerce%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Holiday%20illustration%20with%20ecommerce%20dashboards%20and%20gifts%20representing%20campaign%20decisions%22,%20%22caption%22=%3E%22Planning%20creatives,%20landings%20and%20budget%20keeps%20December%20from%20wrecking%20profitability.%22,%20%22width%22=%3E2816,%20%22height%22=%3E1536%7D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">From opening dozens of tabs to a ready-to-go board</title><link href="https://al6ert.github.io/website.stage/en/news/automation/development/2025/11/14/automate-news-scouting-trello-board/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="From opening dozens of tabs to a ready-to-go board" /><published>2025-11-14T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-14T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://al6ert.github.io/website.stage/en/news/automation/development/2025/11/14/automate-news-scouting-trello-board</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://al6ert.github.io/website.stage/en/news/automation/development/2025/11/14/automate-news-scouting-trello-board/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="how-we-automated-news-scouting">How we automated news scouting</h2>

<p>Does this scene ring a bell?</p>

<p>Every morning someone on the team opens a pile of tabs: institutional sites, blogs, local media… They skim headlines, copy links, check whether they were already shared, decide what deserves to become a task. It is necessary work, yet repetitive, error-prone and nearly impossible to scale.</p>

<p>For us the question became:<br />
<strong>“Can we free people from this manual watch and let them focus on analysing and deciding, not on collecting?”</strong></p>

<h3 id="the-starting-point-a-routine-that-burns-time">The starting point: a routine that burns time</h3>

<p>Our situation looked exactly like this:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Multiple sites and sources, some with RSS and some without it.</li>
  <li>Manual review every single day.</li>
  <li>Risk of forgetting sources, duplicating stories or reacting too late.</li>
</ul>

<p>The outcome: many hours invested in “searching” and very few in <strong>interpreting and acting</strong>.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="the-goal-an-assistant-that-prepares-the-working-board">The goal: an “assistant” that prepares the working board</h3>

<p>We framed a very simple objective:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Every morning, without anyone lifting a finger, we want a list of fresh headlines already waiting in a Trello board, ready to prioritise and assign.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Practically speaking, that means:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Aggregating headlines from multiple sources.</li>
  <li>Avoiding duplicates (so the same story does not pop up two or three times).</li>
  <li>Keeping only the essentials: title, link, date and origin.</li>
  <li>Leaving everything in a work-friendly format (cards/tasks).</li>
</ul>

<p>No need to download full pages or deal with entire bodies of text: <strong>just useful metadata</strong>.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="how-the-automated-flow-works">How the automated flow works</h3>

<p>Picture a very disciplined “digital assistant” that, every day:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Visits the predefined sources (sites, blogs, RSS…).</li>
  <li>Checks what is new compared with the previous run.</li>
  <li>Verifies whether a story was already captured to avoid duplicates.</li>
  <li>Creates a card in a board (Trello in our case) with the basic info.</li>
  <li>Stores a historical log in a spreadsheet so we can audit and analyse trends.</li>
  <li>If something breaks (for example, a site changes its layout), it notifies the team on Slack so it doesn’t go unnoticed.</li>
</ol>

<p>The result: the team no longer “hunts” across the internet — <strong>they open the board and immediately decide what to do with each headline.</strong></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="what-changed-in-our-day-to-day">What changed in our day to day</h3>

<p>Numbers will vary by organisation, yet the impact showed up fast for us:</p>

<ul>
  <li>We went from spending <strong>60–90 minutes a day</strong> reviewing sources…</li>
  <li>…to investing <strong>10–15 minutes</strong> reviewing a board that is already prepared.</li>
  <li>Human errors dropped (forgetting sources, repeating stories, missing something relevant).</li>
  <li>Prioritisation improved: everything arrives with the same format and quality.</li>
  <li>We gained a historical dataset to spot trends: publishing spikes, frequency by source, and more.</li>
</ul>

<p>In short: <strong>less operational effort, more analytical capacity.</strong></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="challenges-we-had-to-solve">Challenges we had to solve</h3>

<p>Along the way we faced several hurdles that may help if you plan something similar:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Very different sources</strong>: some sites are static, others change often, some have RSS, others don’t.</li>
  <li><strong>Silent layout changes</strong>: if a site redesigns itself, the system might stop “understanding” it, so we added clear alerts when that happens.</li>
  <li><strong>Dates and formats all over the place</strong>: normalising that metadata was essential.</li>
  <li><strong>Duplicate prevention</strong>: sometimes a story tweaks its URL; the system still has to recognise it.</li>
  <li><strong>Being respectful with the sites we visit</strong>: this is not about hammering them with thousands of requests per minute, but about acting responsibly.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h3 id="design-choices-that-keep-it-maintainable">Design choices that keep it maintainable</h3>

<p>Beyond the technical bits, some design decisions made the difference:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>A single data model for every source</strong>: all stories are stored with the same fields, which simplifies analysis and future integrations.</li>
  <li><strong>Adding new sources without rewrites</strong>: each source follows a clear “contract”, so scaling up does not break everything.</li>
  <li><strong>Actionable alerts</strong>: whenever something fails, the message points to the source, the issue and where to start looking.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h3 id="a-quick-technical-snapshot">A quick technical snapshot</h3>

<p>For the tech-curious, here is the short version:</p>

<ul>
  <li>We built it with <strong>Python</strong>, using small modules that know how to read each source type.</li>
  <li>The automated run always follows the same steps: extract, validate, normalise, deduplicate and create tasks.</li>
  <li>We use lightweight integrations with <strong>Trello</strong> (cards), <strong>Google Sheets</strong> (historical log) and <strong>Slack</strong> (alerts).</li>
  <li>It runs automatically every day in a reproducible environment.</li>
</ul>

<p>For the end user, the only thing that matters is that it <strong>behaves reliably and predictably</strong>, not the implementation details.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="what-could-come-next">What could come next?</h3>

<p>Now that the foundation is ready, a few ideas emerge:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Use AI to provide a short daily summary of the captured stories.</li>
  <li>Use AI-driven filters to highlight key headlines or discard irrelevant ones based on predefined criteria.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>

<p>The real value of this project is not the code — it is the <strong>shift in focus</strong>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Experts stop spending hours “watching” sources and can devote their time to what brings the most value: interpreting, deciding and executing.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>An automated flow turns scattered sites and channels into a structured stream of actionable tasks.<br />
It is the difference between <strong>reacting late to the news</strong> and <strong>finding a ready-to-go board every morning</strong>.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="want-to-learn-more">Want to learn more?</h3>

<p>If your organisation is also spending too many hours monitoring sites and newsletters, let’s talk.</p>

<div class="text-center not-prose"><a class="btn btn-primary text-primary-content btn-lg" href="mailto:mail@persualia.com">Contact us</a></div>

<p>I will share a visual outline of the architecture and the steps we follow to automate this flow, tailored to your context.</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#Automation</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#InformationManagement</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#Productivity</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#DigitalTransformation</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#News</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#Communication</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#DataDriven</code></p>]]></content><author><name>Albert Pérez</name></author><category term="news" /><category term="automation" /><category term="development" /><category term="automation" /><category term="productivity" /><category term="trello" /><category term="workflow" /><category term="information-management" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How we automated headline collection so every morning the team finds a Trello board ready to prioritize without spending an hour visiting websites.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://al6ert.github.io/website.stage/en/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/assets/images/posts/2025-11-14-automatitzar-cerca-noticies-tauler-trello%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Automating%20news%20scouting%20with%20a%20flow%20that%20captures%20headlines%20and%20delivers%20them%20into%20a%20ready-made%20Trello%20board%22,%20%22caption%22=%3E%22From%20manual%20monitoring%20to%20an%20automated%20board:%20fewer%20tabs,%20more%20decisions.%22,%20%22width%22=%3E1344,%20%22height%22=%3E768%7D" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://al6ert.github.io/website.stage/en/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/assets/images/posts/2025-11-14-automatitzar-cerca-noticies-tauler-trello%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Automating%20news%20scouting%20with%20a%20flow%20that%20captures%20headlines%20and%20delivers%20them%20into%20a%20ready-made%20Trello%20board%22,%20%22caption%22=%3E%22From%20manual%20monitoring%20to%20an%20automated%20board:%20fewer%20tabs,%20more%20decisions.%22,%20%22width%22=%3E1344,%20%22height%22=%3E768%7D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">META VS. EUROPE: when politics turns into silence</title><link href="https://al6ert.github.io/website.stage/en/news/marketing/ngo/2025/10/07/meta-vs-europe-when-policy-turns-to-silence/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="META VS. EUROPE: when politics turns into silence" /><published>2025-10-07T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-07T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://al6ert.github.io/website.stage/en/news/marketing/ngo/2025/10/07/meta-vs-europe-when-policy-turns-to-silence</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://al6ert.github.io/website.stage/en/news/marketing/ngo/2025/10/07/meta-vs-europe-when-policy-turns-to-silence/"><![CDATA[<p>This week Meta started blocking ads it labels as “political debate”. The move arrives after months of tension with the European Union over advertising transparency.</p>

<p>To dodge legal headaches, Meta chose the easiest firewall: <strong>ban every single ad that could be interpreted as opening a political debate</strong>. The result? Humanitarian, public health, education or social awareness campaigns are being thrown into the same basket. Campaigns exposing the genocide in Gaza, raising funds for global emergencies or pushing public health messages can now be blocked for being “political”.</p>

<p>It does not surprise me: <strong>transparency has never been Meta’s strong suit</strong>. Yet I am not shocked either that today’s political climate fuels the urge to control discourse via digital channels. <strong>Political debate has become uncomfortable for certain ideologies.</strong> When that happens, those in power tend to regulate, filter and simplify whatever they cannot control. This time, the silence does not only hit political parties —it mutes the voices that speak up for others. Foundations, NGOs and organisations trying to raise awareness or educate now see their ads tagged as “political” and automatically rejected.</p>

<p>At <strong>Persualia</strong> we know this territory well. For years, for different reasons, we have had to communicate social or political messages without using Meta’s disclaimer. <strong>It is frustrating and has caused more than one headache</strong>, but it has also forced us to find creative paths to keep meaningful messages alive.</p>

<h3 id="the-challenge-now-is-to-learn-how-to-communicate-differently">The challenge now is to learn how to communicate differently</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Move the most activist messages away from Meta, into owned channels or earned media where tone and freedom are not constrained.</li>
  <li>Inside Meta, focus the narrative on the human, empathetic side so the message is not flagged as a political debate.</li>
  <li>Craft content that sparks personal involvement —participation, reflection, small actions— without fuelling polarization.</li>
  <li>And above all, continue to talk about justice, rights and social causes with strategic and narrative intelligence.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Despite the obstacles, I remain optimistic:</strong> alternatives exist, there are new routes, and creativity is still the best tool to carry on.</p>

<p><strong>What do you think?</strong><br />
Do you believe this new Meta policy will end up shaping which social messages reach people?</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#socialadvertising</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#NGO</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#Meta</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#transparency</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#purposedrivencommunication</code></p>]]></content><author><name>Coral Costa</name></author><category term="news" /><category term="marketing" /><category term="ngo" /><category term="social-advertising" /><category term="NGO" /><category term="Meta" /><category term="transparency" /><category term="purpose-driven-communication" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week Meta started blocking ads it labels as “political debate”, after a long standoff with the European Union around advertising transparency.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://al6ert.github.io/website.stage/en/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/assets/images/posts/2025-10-07-meta-vs-europa-cuando-la-politica-se-convierte-en-silencio%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Man%20chained%20between%20Meta%20and%20the%20European%20Union%20with%20blocked%20social%20icons%22,%20%22caption%22=%3E%22Ad%20blocking%20traps%20social%20messages%20between%20Meta%20and%20the%20EU.%22,%20%22width%22=%3E1344,%20%22height%22=%3E768%7D" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://al6ert.github.io/website.stage/en/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/assets/images/posts/2025-10-07-meta-vs-europa-cuando-la-politica-se-convierte-en-silencio%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Man%20chained%20between%20Meta%20and%20the%20European%20Union%20with%20blocked%20social%20icons%22,%20%22caption%22=%3E%22Ad%20blocking%20traps%20social%20messages%20between%20Meta%20and%20the%20EU.%22,%20%22width%22=%3E1344,%20%22height%22=%3E768%7D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>